<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog for Tech Enjoyers</title>
    <link>https://example.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog for Tech Enjoyers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 14:00:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minimalistic SwiftUI GUI for Yt-dlp</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/swiftui-ytdl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 14:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/swiftui-ytdl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Yt-dlp and ffmpeg and two of my favorite command-line tools. But I keep having to look up how to use them! For this reason, I made a simple SwiftUI GUI that has three simple commands built-in. The user only has to choose and output folder and a file type (mp3 [audio only], opus [audio only] and mkv [audio and video]) and click the download button. The binaries for yt-dlp and ffmpeg are downloaded from the most official sources I could find at runtime.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fake GitHub commits</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/github-commit-faking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 14:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/github-commit-faking/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In Git, you have to set your E-Mail address using the command:&#xA;&amp;#34;git config --global user.email myEmail@example.com&amp;#34; The problem is that when you now commit to a GitHub repository, GitHub will map this E-Mail to a GitHub account (if it exists) and then show the commit as if that account would have committed it. This has two direct implications:&#xA;You can find out the GitHub account of people you know the E-Mail of (security problem) You can use this technique to fake contribute to your repo to make it seem more trustworthy The E-Mail addresses of popular devs are often known from mailing lists etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated self-hosted GitLab backups to Dropbox using a Python script on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/python-gitlab-backup-rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/python-gitlab-backup-rpi/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I prefer self-hosted GitLab over uploading my code to GitHub. The only disadvantage is that I need to take care of backups myself in case a hard drive dies or gets stolen. Therefore, I wrote a simple Python script that runs on my Raspberry Pi twice a week, which backs up my GitLab config and data and uploads them to my Dropbox. Specifically, I am using the free community edition of GitLab on my RPI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use APNs with Golang and Google Firebase &#43; Firestore</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/golang-firebase-apns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/golang-firebase-apns/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you are building a SwiftUI app like me, you will probably encounter a situation where you want to be able to send out Push Notifications to your users. Google Firebase offers a free plan (completely free with pretty generous usage) that allows you to do just that. Combined with Google Firestore you even get a small database where you can store device tokens (your users will write their device token to the database by using your app, and you send out notifications to all device tokens).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wxwidgets macOS guide to compile universal binaries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/wxwidget-macos-universal-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 14:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/wxwidget-macos-universal-binary/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I wanted to publish my wxwidgets project &amp;ldquo;D2R Runeword Calculator&amp;rdquo; which I already blogged about, to the macOS App Store. In order to do this with wxwidgets, you are advised to create statically-linked binaries that run both on x86_64 and arm64. But the instructions in the wxwidgets tutorials are outdated and lack crucial information. It took me a few hours, but I figured out how it can be done on macOS Ventura (13.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackintosh #3: Running Sonoma on XPS 9370 (i7 8550u - 4k display)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/hackintosh-xps9370/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 08:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/hackintosh-xps9370/</guid>
      <description>Introduction macOS Sonoma is the newest macOS version (which always is a challenge for Hackintosh) and installing it on an older laptop is an extra challenge. In this post I will talk about how I successfully hackintoshed the XPS 9370. Note that currently online installers do not work for Sonoma, so you require an Apple machine or a Hackintosh to create an offline installer (first you create a FAT32 partition called EFI (Size around 200MB), then you make an Mac OS Extended (Journaled) partition called MyVolume, then you follow this Apple guide).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Stable Diffusion as Discord Emote Generator</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/stable-diffusion-gopher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 22:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/stable-diffusion-gopher/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Stable Diffusion is an open-source deep learning text-to-image model that does not have any filters and works offline. There are a few controversies around it (e.g., it has been trained on copyrighted artwork but gives the user of Stable Diffusion the rights to all images it spits out, and it does not have filters and can be used to create all sorts of weird content). It works offline and poses a threat to existing businesses that sell AI-generated images (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blocking Twitch Ads by piping the stream to VLC</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/twitch-adblock-streamlink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 08:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/twitch-adblock-streamlink/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Twitch keeps changing their backend, and it recently became more difficult to block ads. A few years ago, any ad blocker seemed to work just fine. Then they changed their code, and uBlock Origin, Adblock Plus, etc. all fail to remove ads. While there are still browser plugins that promise to block Twitch ads, many of them are potentially shady, as they route your traffic over some proxy server that does who-knows-what.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackintosh #2: Running Ventura using Haswell CPU and a spoofed AMD RX 6650 XT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/hackintosh-ventura-rx6650xt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 08:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/hackintosh-ventura-rx6650xt/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In my previous post, I wrote about how I used the following hardware to run Monterey (an older macOS version):&#xA;Intel i5 4400 (Haswell) MSI B85-G41 Intel AX210 BT/Wi-Fi As you can see, this build did not have a dGPU. For this reason, I bought an AMD RX 6650 XT and added it to this computer. This GPU officially is not supported either (so it would have been easier to get an AMD RX 6600 instead), but you can do GPU ID spoofing to make it work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackintosh in 2023</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/hackintosh-project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/hackintosh-project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I always enjoy testing different tech-related things, such as different OSes. Having used Windows, Linux, iOS and Android, I thought it was about time I tried macOS for the first time. I prefer not to be trapped within Apple&amp;rsquo;s walled garden, so instead of purchasing a Mac, I tried to give new life to old hardware I still had laying around. In the context of Hackintosh, it is important to know which hardware is supported for what.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encrypt data using Argon2 and AES-GCM-256 in Python</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/aes-argon2-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 08:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/aes-argon2-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have bought insecure Mifare Classic 1k cards (Crypto-1 is broken and should not be used), so the only way to securely store data on these cards is with a tamperproof, modern encryption algorithm. So I decided to learn some basics and write a simple Python script that allows me to do this. AES-GCM was chosen because it features tags that are used to determine whether encrypted data was tempered with or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golang&#39;s unintuitive pitfalls</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/golang-unintuitive-pitfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 08:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/golang-unintuitive-pitfalls/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Disclaimer: I have just recently picked up the language, so don&amp;rsquo;t expect this post to be a deep analysis of advanced Golang concepts. Instead, think of it as the perception of Golang from someone who already knows other programming languages but just recently started to learn Go. As with most things, there is stuff that I really like about Golang, and there are quite a few things that truly annoy me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; runeword calculator GUI for Diablo 2 Resurrected</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/d2-runewords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 22:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/d2-runewords/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Diablo 2 Resurrected is one of my favorite games of all time, but there are a lot of things you need to remember. There are various online tools (the idea of a runeword calculator is not new), but many of them have a terrible User Interface, are outdated, or are located on slow websites that autoplay Twitch streams when you open them. So I decided to learn how to use wxWidgets by making an assistant GUI tool for my favorite game!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python script for Llama 2 conversations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/llama-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 18:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/llama-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have played around a bit with the new Llama 2 LLM, more specifically with the 13B parameter Huggingface version that you can download here. In order to run it, check out Llama.cpp. It has precise setup instructions, so I will assume you get that running on your own. What I did not enjoy was having to type long commands into my Windows cmd every time, so I decided to write a short Python script that runs the process in the background and displays the output in the Python shell in real-time (well, almost).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to authenticate and write data to Mifare Classic 1k using ACS ACR122U</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/nfc-mifare-acr122u/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 14:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/nfc-mifare-acr122u/</guid>
      <description>Goal I bought some Mifare Classic 1k tags and all Android/iOS apps I tried (official NXP apps, NFC Tools Pro and Mifare Classic Tool) failed to write data to my tags! Mifare Classic tags are not as straight-forward as e.g. NTAG ones because they are proprietary (they do technically support NDEF, but it&amp;rsquo;s not a compatible as you would like it to be). So to write data to these tags using my ACS ACR122U, I use the Windows Smart Card API to communicate with the NFC reader.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NFC in 2023</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/nfc-overview-and-playing-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 14:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/nfc-overview-and-playing-around/</guid>
      <description>Overview of NFC tags NFC was invented in 2002 by Sony and NXP Semiconductors. Since then, a lot of different standards and tags have been created, so here is a basic overview of commonly used tags and their classification. To simplify things, commonly used NFC tags can usually be put into one of five forum types:&#xA;Forum type 1 (read-only) Forum type 2 (usually read/write and more storage than type 1) Forum type 3 (mainly used in Japan) Forum type 4 (like type 2, but with more storage and features and a higher cost than type 2) Forum type 5 (highest communication range, not commonly used by consumers) These forum types help cluster different tags into categories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate any weekday</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/how-to-calculate-any-weekday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/how-to-calculate-any-weekday/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I once read about a simple way to calculate what day of the week any given date is. All you need to do is remember a few numbers and do basic math in your head. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&#xA;What you need to remember Each weekday has an assigned number:&#xA;Sunday = 0 Monday = 1 Tuesday = 2 Wednesday = 3 Thursday = 4 Friday = 5 Saturday = 6 Also remember the following list for the months:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mine your username</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/mine-your-username/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 21:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/mine-your-username/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So you wanted to sign up for a website but couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of a cool username that wasn&amp;rsquo;t already taken? No way, I was in that same situation! So I decided to write a C++ program that takes your base name (e.g., &amp;ldquo;cafe&amp;rdquo;) and adds a few numbers. The idea is to generate usernames that, when hashed using SHA256 or KECCAK256 result in strings that contain your base name again!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to write a tutorial</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/how-to-write-a-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 14:00:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/how-to-write-a-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So you have decided to write a tutorial? Remember that there is nothing more frustrating than being a beginner at something, trying to become better at that thing by going through a tutorial and then being unable to complete the tutorial due to errors or unclear instructions. If you are not willing to write a good tutorial, it is better to not write a tutorial at all. So here are a few basic things that you should consider when trying to write a good tutorial.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
